（ナルト）これは。
This is…
Okay! Which one's the fake?!
さあて
なりすまし野郎はどいつだ？
ん？
グハッ！
この！
Why you…!
グハッ！
What're you doing?!
Don't attack so recklessly!
（カルイ）なにやってる！　そいつの
間合いにうかつに飛び込むな！
ん？　あいつ　どっかで…。
That guy… Where have I seen him before?
（みんな）うわ～っ！
What? A samurai with ninja skills?!
なに！　侍のくせに技使うのか。
離れろ。　もっと間合いをとるんだ。
Get back!
Put more space between you!
What're you doing?!
Where's the Sealing Corps?!
何やってんだ。
封印班はいねえのかよ？
ああ　なりきり野郎のおかげで
本体と離れちまった。
They got separated from
the main company, thanks to those fakes.
Right now,
we're waiting for reinforcements.
今は援軍待ちだ…
って誰だ　てめえ！
Hey, who the hell are you?!
ヘッ　誰だはねえだろう。
What do you mean,
"Who the hell are you"?!
お前　気の済むまで俺のこと
ボコボコにしただろうがよ。
You totally beat me up yesterday.
You'd better not have forgotten!
忘れてんじゃねえよ！
You're Naruto?!
お前　ナルトか。
おう。
Yeah.
ずいぶんと違っちまってて
わからねえだろ。
You changed so much,
so I didn't recognize you!
By the way, who is he?
ところで　あいつは？
ああ
穢土転生された侍のようだが→
Oh, he's a Reanimation…
He looks like a samurai,
but he's super strong!
すげえ強ぇ。
侍？
A samurai?
（タテワキ）さがれ　忍ども。
貴様らには何の恨みもない。
Get back, shinobi!
I bear you no grudge!
だが　この体
操られていてはしかたがないのだ。
However, this body is
being manipulated
and I have no control over myself.
それに　それがし侍などでは…。
Furthermore, I am not a samurai…
鉄の国をとうに捨てた身。
いわゆる浪人…。
I abandoned
the Land of Iron ages ago…
I'm much like a ronin…
いや違う。　それがしは…。
No, that's not right. I am…
Old man…
おっちゃん？
まさか　タテワキのおっちゃんか？
Don't tell me
you're Old Man Tatewaki?!
いかにも。　それがしの名は　タテワキ。
Tatewaki, that is my name indeed.
そういう　おぬしは？
あいつを知ってんのか　ナルト。
Who might you be?
You know him, Naruto?
ナルト？　ナルトだと？
Naruto? Did you say "Naruto"?
そうだ　タテワキのおっちゃん。
Yeah! It's me, Naruto,
Old Man Tatewaki!
お前は生きていたのだな。
So you're still alive!
教えてくれ　２人の行方を。
あれからどうなったのかを。
Tell me! Those two…
What happened to those two?
DO YOUR BEST, EVERYONE
This mission is a direct request
from the Feudal Lord of the Land of Fire!
（綱手）今回の任務は火の国
大名から　じきじきの依頼だ。
いわば　国の政にかかわる任務だと
肝に銘じておけ。
Bear in mind that this mission involves
the nation's governance.
（シカマル）めんどくさそうだな。
（いの）そんなこと言わない。
What a pain.
Don't say that.
（チョウジ）ウナ肝なら好きだけど。
Will we have time to eat?
Talking about food again?
お前ってば
また食いもんの話かよ。
Why do you care?
Besides, how come you're here?!
なんだよ。　だいたいなんで
ナルトがいるんだよ？
Naruto will be joining
Shikamaru's team for this mission.
ナルトは今回
シカマルの班に加わってもらう。
へ？
それで　ナルトを加えた俺たちに→
Huh?
So what's this mission that
we're supposed to go on with Naruto?
やらせようっていう任務は
何なんです？
まぁ　簡単にいえば人さらいだ。
Well, put bluntly…
It's a kidnapping.
– Huh?!
（みんな）え～っ！
The young lord is a hostage
in a castle in this nation.
此の国の城に　彼の国の若殿が
人質として預けられている。
その若殿を木ノ葉隠れの仕業と
バレないように→
The mission is to kidnap
the young lord
さらってくることが任務。
without being discovered.
So we kidnap the young lord,
and then what?
でもさ　若殿さらってどうすんだ？
Are we going to demand a ransom?
身代金とか取るとか。
それだと政と関係ねえだろ。
Get real. This is a political matter.
彼の国は此の国と
同盟を結んでいるが→
His homeland has a treaty
with this nation.
それを破棄して　新たに火の国と
同盟を結ぶつもりだ。
But they want to nullify the treaty
in order to establish
an alliance with the Land of Fire.
そこで　此の国に人質として
預けられている若殿を→
So the mission is
to kidnap the young lord
who is being held hostage here
and take him home.
ひそかに彼の国へ
連れ戻そうというわけだ。
ばあちゃん
ランクで言ったらどのくらい？
So Granny, what rank does this fall into?
Normally, it would be a B-rank mission.
基本はＢランクだが
城の守りによっては→
However, depending on
how fortified the castle is,
Ａに　はね上がるかもな。
it may be bumped up to
an A-rank mission.
Now you're talking!
That makes it worth going!
よっしゃ！　そのほうが
やりがいあるってばよ。
いや　俺たちは
そういうのいいから。
Hey, we don't concern ourselves
with stuff like that.
と　あいつらには言ったが
此の国の周囲には→
Anyway, I warned them
that there's been suspicious activity
around this nation.
現在　きな臭い動きがある。
（ヤマト）
彼の国が同盟を解消するのも→
And it has something to do
with the fact
それが関係しているという
わけですね。
that his nation wants
to cancel the treaty?
事がねじれたら　ランクはＡにも
Ｓにもはね上がる。
If things go awry,
this mission will become an
A or S-rank very quickly.
よって　バックアップ要員として→
I want you as ANBU to
stay in the shadows
暗部のお前に背後に
控えていてもらいたい。
and watch their backs.
表に出るタイミングは？
Under what circumstances
do I reveal myself?
I want you to gather intel
on anything suspicious too…
きな臭い動きとやらの情報を
集める必要もある。
現場での判断に任せる。
わかりました。
I'll leave it up to your judgment.
Understood.
The A-Rank Mission:
Food Fight!
（デイダラ）なぁ　サソリの旦那→
Hey, Mister Sasori…
最近　任務が
セコくなってんじゃねえかな　うん。
We've been getting
petty missions lately.
今は依頼されたら
なんでも引き受けているからな。
That's because we accept
every request we get.
Money-making and mercenary jobs
don't have an iota of art, hmm.
金儲けとか雇われ戦争ばっかじゃ
芸術性のカケラも感じられねえよ。
うん。
そこんとこは同感だが→
I agree, but we have no choice
but to listen to the organization.
組織の方針には
従うしかねえだろ。
世界征服への道のりは遠いな。
World conquest seems a long way off.
（飛段）おい。
– Hey!
– Huh?
Hey, you're late.
（デイダラ）おう　遅かったな。
We have new missions.
（角都）新しい任務を持ってきた。
１つは金儲けで　１つは戦争だ。
One is money-making.
The other is war.
金儲けは　そそられねえ。
あぁ。
Making money doesn't excite me.
Yeah…
Well then, Hidan and I'll take
the money-making job.
（角都）では
俺と飛段で金儲けのほうに行く。
Hey, hey! Don't just decide!
おい！　おいおい！
何　勝手に決めてんだ！
I'm not interested in money either!
俺だって
カネには興味がねえんだよ！
Someone has to do it.
誰かがやるしかねえんだ。
サソリもデイダラも
戦争のほうがいいってんだ。
Sasori and Deidara both prefer war.
Let's not bicker about this.
こんなことで揉めることはない。
てめえら！　あとで覚えとけよ！
Hey, guys… You owe me later!
So? Who're we fighting?
で　戦争の相手は？
（角都）国ひとつだ　小国だがな。
One nation…a small one.
And what's special about
this small nation?
（デイダラ）その小国が　何だってんだ？
（角都）小国ってのは
身軽に立ち位置を変えるからな。
The political standing of
a small nation changes all the time.
Anyway, the request comes from
a large nation who wants its territory.
むしろ自分の領地にしちまおう
って考えた大国の依頼だ。
おもしれえ。
Interesting…
（いの）あれね　此の国の城って。
That's the nation's castle?
若殿の誘拐か…
バレないようにってのが問題だね。
Kidnap the young lord, huh…
The problem is keeping it a secret.
We're supposed to find a way with
シカマルの影真似とか
いのの心転身の術で→
Shikamaru's Shadow Possession
or Ino's Mind Transfer Jutsu?
まぁ
なんとかしろってこったろう？
いいや　任務の要はチョウジとナルトだ。
Nope. You and Choji are
the key players in this mission.
Us?
僕たちが？
あぁ。
Yeah. Choji, you're entering
a contest attended by the lord.
チョウジには　御膳試合に出てもらう。
普通なら
城に余所者なんか入れないが→
Normally, unauthorized persons
can't enter the castle.
御膳試合の参加者なら別だ。
But participants will be allowed in.
《御膳試合っていうと…》
A contest being attended
by the lord is like…
((わぁ～！))
なんで僕が　そんな役を…。
Why do I have to take part in it?!
チョウジじゃ
簡単に負けちまうってばよ！
Choji's gonna lose right away!
No, it's food fight.
いや　御膳試合じゃなくて
お膳試合なんだよ。
何よ　お膳試合って！？
What? A food fight?
喜べ　チョウジ
簡単に言えば　大食い選手権だ。
You should be happy, Choji.
Simply put, it's an eating contest.
No kidding, Shikamaru?!
本当？　シカマル！
Being a contestant in an eating contest
is a mission made in heaven!
任務で大食い選手権に
出られるなんて　僕は幸せだよ。
じゃあ　俺は
何をすればいいんだってばよ！？
And what am I supposed to do?
あぁ　ナルトには
チョウジの手引きで城内に潜入し→
Well, while Choji creates a diversion,
you will sneak into the castle,
use your specialty Transformation Jutsu…
お得意の変化の術で
若殿と入れ替わって→
to switch places with
the young lord and
buy us time while we make
our escape with the real one.
本物が脱出する
時間稼ぎをしてもらう。
ナルトの若殿で大丈夫なの？
You're okay with Naruto
as the young lord?
What's that supposed to mean?!
どういう意味だってばよ！？
そういう意味よ！
Exactly that.
She's right.
そうだね…
若殿に変化するんだから→
He's gonna be a young lord.
If he says he wants ramen for lunch,
his cover will be blown right away.
昼ご飯にラーメン食べたい
なんて言ったら　すぐバレちゃうよ。
うむ…。
お前らなぁ！
Aw listen, guys…
だってばよ　とか
言っちゃダメなのよ。
And watch how you speak.
Aw man, you don't have to tell me!
そんなことぐらい
わかってるってばよ！
– Do you really get it?
– Of course, I do!
（いの）本当　わかってんの？
わかってるってばよ！
63RD FOOD CONTEST
PRELIMINARY SITE
参加者は前へ！
Participants, step forward!
じゃあ　行くか！
うん！
Let's go!
Yeah!
此の国の繁栄　五穀豊穣を願い
これより　御膳試合を行う。
In hopes of prosperity for this nation
and an abundance of crops…
we will begin the contest.
優勝者には　殿より過分なる栄誉と
褒美が賜られるゆえ→
The winner will be duly
honored by the lord
and shall receive a generous reward.
So everyone, do your best…
皆　日ごろの実力を発揮し
見苦しき行為のなきように食せよ。
and partake of the foods
with dignity and grace.
まぁ
チョウジだったら予選は軽いわね。
The preliminaries will be easy for Choji.
でも　なんでナルトまで出たの？
– But why Naruto?
– Ramen, ramen…
– There's an event featuring ramen.
（シカマル）種目に
ラーメンがあるらしいんだと。
ラーメン以外は人並みでしょ？
あいつ。
まあな。
Other than ramen,
he's like everyone else.
Yeah, well…
予選１回戦は…　饅頭対決である！
For the first event…!
Bean jam cakes!
ラーメンじゃないの！？
Huh?! Not ramen?!
城下町の名店　アマアマ庵の品である！
From the well-known Ama-ama An
in the castle town!
それでは…　心して食せよ～！
On your mark!
Eat your fill!
やっぱりナルトじゃダメね。
あ…　いの　あそこ。
Naruto can't cut it, after all.
Ino, over there…
Huh?
あの人たちが…。
That's them?
Yeah.
ああ　あれが　件の若殿だ。
That's the young lord in question…
そんなことより　あいつだ。
え？
Never mind them. Look at him.
Huh?
（いの）あの大きな人？
（シカマル）ああ。
That big guy?
此の国は　元侍を
警護に雇っている。　その隊長だ。
This nation hires former samurai
as guards.
He's the captain of the guards.
俺たちの任務の
最大の難関は　あいつだな。
And the biggest threat
to our operation.
それまでじゃ！
Time!
大丈夫？　ナルト。
大丈夫じゃないかも…。
Are you okay, Naruto?
Maybe not.
食べきれなかった者は
去るのじゃ！
Contestants who were unable
to finish must withdraw!
はぁ…　何とか予選突破か…。
I barely made it through.
引き続き　予選２回戦を行う！
すぐ２回戦！？
We continue on to the second round!
A second round now?!
予選２回戦は　ラーメン対決じゃ！
The second round is…
a ramen-eating contest!
Ramen? Right after this?!
ラーメン！？　このタイミングで…　ゲッ！
城下町の名店
ギトギト亭の　ひと品であ～る！
Ramen from the famous
castle town shop, Gito Gito Tei.
何だ…　この大きさ。
Look at the size of this…
心して食せよ！
Pace yourselves…
う　うまい…　だけど→
T-Tasty, but…
背脂ギトギト系は　今…。
This greasiness right now…
う　うまい…　だけど→
T-Tasty, but…these voluminous
thick noodles right now…
ボリューム感ある太麺は今…。
チャーシューも　すごくおいしいよ
肉汁たっぷりで。
The roast pork is amazing
and they're generous with the broth.
《無理だ
こんな　うまいラーメンなのに》
I can't.
– Even though it tastes so good…
– It's a deluxe fishcake too.
ダメだ～　これ以上は食えねえ。
I can't… I can't take another bite.
食いたい…　でも　食えねえ。
I want to, but I can't…
食ったら　大変なことになる。
If I eat any more…
I'll be in trouble…
でも　食いたい…　でも　食えねえ！
And yet, I want to eat…
But I can't!
皆　やるのう　うん。
Everyone seems up to the task. Hmm…
（千代）父上　千代も見ていたら→
Father, watching them
has made me hungry.
お腹が空いてまいりました。
うむ　先ほどの　まんじゅうを
持ってこさせよう。　これ。
How about some of those
bean jam cakes from earlier?
Someone…
シュウ様は？
What about you, Lord Shu?
I'd like to try that ramen.
（シュウ）私は　あのラーメンとやらに
興味があります。
あぁ　ラーメンは　いかん。
なぜです？
Oh, not ramen.
Why not?
ぬるくて　麺がブヨブヨで　いかん。
It's lukewarm and the noodles
are too soft.
大名様には
お毒見のあとに出しますゆえ→
The taster must check
my lord's food for poison,
どうしても　麺が　のびます。
so the noodles always get soft.
うむ　まんじゅうは　よいのう。
のびぬ。
Bean jam cakes are wonderful.
They stay the same.
そうですか　残念です。
Is that so? How unfortunate.
シュウ様　そろそろ　お時間です。
Lord Shu, it's almost time.
え？　今日は　御膳試合なのに？
Huh? But there's a contest today.
関係ありません。
では　まいりましょう。
はい…。
That doesn't matter.
Now, let us go.
All right.
アハハハハ　皆　すごいのう。
Everyone is amazing…
残り　３０秒！
Thirty seconds left!
（シカマル）チョウジのやつ
ライバルの目星をつけたみたいだな。
Seems Choji's sussed out his rivals…
あと５秒！　４　３　２　１　０！
Five seconds left…
Four…three…two…one…
Zero… Stop eating!
それまで！
夕刻より　決勝戦を行う。
The final round will be held
at sunset.
見事　完食した者のみ
城内に入るのじゃ。
Only those who have finished their bowls
will be allowed inside the castle.
よし！
うぅ　チョウジ…。
Yes!
Choji.
頑張れよ…。
任せて。
Do your best!
Just leave it to me.
仕込みは終わった。
俺たちも昼飯に行くか。
Okay, the groundwork is laid.
How about we go get some lunch?
ハァ　ハァ…。
だぁ～！
Watch your side.
脇があまい！
動きを止めない！
Always keep moving.
そう　しっかり相手を見て。
Yes, keep your eyes on your opponent.
まっすぐ下がらない！
Don't step straight back.
あっ！
うっ　うぅ…。
拾って。
もう動けない。
まだです。
Pick it up.
I can't move anymore.
It's not over.
こんなことして何になるんだ！
僕は人質だ。
What's the point of training anyway?
I'm a hostage.
All I have to do is behave.
おとなしくしているだけで
いいんだ。
人の運命など　わからぬものです。
Fate is unpredictable.
Mine…won't change.
僕は　このままだ…。
は～っ！　やぁ～！
タテワキ！
Tatewaki!
動けましたな。
I see that you can move.
修業が厳しすぎます。
Your training is too harsh.
今日は　これまで。
That's all for today.
大丈夫？　シュウ様。
Are you all right, Lord Shu?
タテワキは　僕が嫌いなんだ。
Tatewaki doesn't like me.
職務に忠実なだけよ。　侍だもの。
He's just being dutiful.
After all, he's a samurai.
元　侍だよ。
A former samurai.
選ばれし者たちよ
よくぞ勝ち上がってきた。
Chosen ones…
I commend you for making it
to the finals.
No need to be reserved.
遠慮は要らん　おおいに食せ。
Eat your fill.
（みんな）はっ！
よ～し　チョウジ　優勝しちまえ！
All right! Win this thing, Choji!
ダメだ。
えっ　なんで？
– He can't win.
– Huh?
Why not?
狙いは２番。
それが　若殿脱出の作戦だ。
We want him to come in second.
That's the strategy for
the young lord's escape.
ふ～ん。
なるほどね。
I see…
決勝戦！　第一の儀は　早食い勝負。
The first of the final events
is a speed-eating contest…
寿司　１００貫じゃ！
of 100 pieces of sushi.
上位３名のみが
最終決戦に進める。
The top three contestants will
advance to the final.
城下町の名店　ネタネタ寿司の
品である！
These are from the renowned
Neta Neta Sushi in the castle town…
Eat wisely!
心して食せよ！
– Okay, let's get going, Naruto.
– Right!
よし　いくぞ　ナルト。
おう！
– Ino.
– I know.
いの。
わかってる。
忍法　心転身の術。
Ninja Art…
Mind Transfer Jutsu!
すごい！　シュウ様？
Wow…!
Lord Shu?
厠へまいる。
I'm going to the washroom.
おぉ　今年は　精鋭揃いよのう。
Oh my, what a fine group
we have this year.
へぇ　これが若殿ねぇ。
So this is the young lord.
Make it snappy!
早くして！
変化の術！
Transformation Jutsu!
じゃあ　いってくらぁ。
Okay, I'm off!
Lord Shu, this is a missive
from your father.
シュウ様　本国の父上様より書状です。
お前は？
And you are?
I am a shinobi, and I'm here
at the request of your homeland.
彼の国より依頼を受けた忍です。
完食！
Finished!
なに？　チョウジ　まだ食べてるの！？
What?
Choji's still eating?
Clean your plates…
完食！　それまでじゃ！
and stop!
しばし休憩のあと
この３名で　最終決戦じゃ。
We will take a short break,
then the top three will go on to the final!
あ～　うまかった。
Oh man, that was good.
チョウジったら
ちゃんと段取りわかってんの！？
Choji, do you really know
what you're supposed to do?
寿司もよいな。　のびぬ。
Sushi is wonderful too.
It doesn't get soft.
あっ　シュウ様　お寿司よ。
Lord Shu, have some sushi.
俺…　いや　僕はまだ食欲がなくて。
Nah, I…
I mean, I have no appetite.
そんな　大変。
How unfortunate.
Is something the matter?
（タテワキ）どうかしましたか？
なんでもない。
みんなの食いっぷりに圧倒されて。
It's nothing.
I'm just shocked at how much
everyone can eat…
最終決戦は　焼き肉じゃ。
The last event is…BBQ meat!
《焼き肉！》
Barbecue?!
城下町の名店　ケムケム苑の品である。
From the renowned castle town shop…
Kemu Kemu-en!
心して食せよ！
Eat with care!
上手くいった？
まぁ　今んとこはな。
Did it work?
Well, for now.
おっ　焼き肉だったら
チョウジの楽勝だな。
Oh? If it's barbecue,
it'll be easy for Choji.
それが　そうでもないのよ。
あ？
Well, not really.
Huh?
おぉ　すごいのう。
Oh my… How amazing.
（タマオ）こうなったら…　二刀流！
Damn! Well then,
I'll use my Two-Handed Style!
すごい！　両手で食べてる。
Oh look! She's eating with both hands!
ほっほ！　必殺技を
出してきたようだのう。
She's using a special technique.
（イソノ）ならば　必殺！　ジャグラー！
Huh! Then get a load of this!
Lethal Juggler!
あっ！　あの人も両手で。
Oh, he's using two hands too!
いや　あれは
左手で　皿から肉を網にのせ→
No, he's using his left hand
to put the meat on the grill,
右手で　焼けた肉を食べておる。
and using his right hand
to eat the cooked meat.
左右違う動きをしておるうえ
無駄がない。
Going am
しかし…。
（千代）お箸が見えない！
（タマオ）はやい…。
あれじゃ　チョウジ優勝しちゃうわよ！
チッ！　２番じゃなきゃ
ダメなんだってのに。
《これが…　これが最後の…。
最後の…　ひと口！》
《うっ　動けない！》
完食！
影真似の術　成功。
それまでじゃ！　本年度
御膳試合の優勝者は　イソノじゃ！
やった～！
ハァ～。
やれやれ。
うむ　あっぱれ　見事であった。
負けちゃった。
しようがないよね。
最後に　動きが止まったな。
どれ　褒美をつかわす。
優勝したイソノには　家１軒を賜る。
ははっ！
２位のチョウジには
大きなつづらをつかわす。
ははっ！
３位のタマオには
小さなつづらをつかわす。
ははっ！
では　これにて
御膳試合終了じゃ！
楽しかったわね　シュウ様。
う　うん。
《今ごろ　腹減ってきたってばよ》
皆様　お変わりございませんか？
美空ひばりです。
では最後まで
ごゆっくりお楽しみください。
『木曜８時のコンサート
名曲！にっぽんの歌』２時間スペシャル。